A Finding Aid to the Rose Slivka Papers, circa 1947-2006, in the Archives of American Art AAA.slivrose
Archives of American Art
Rose Slivka papers
circa 1947-2006
AAA.slivrose
Archives of American Art
20.8 Linear feet
The papers of craft expert Rose Slivka, an editor, writer, critic, and educator, measure 20.8 linear feet and date from circa 1947-2006. The papers reflect Slivka's work with associations and universities to encourage the recognition of crafts as an international and broadly defined art form. The routine business of publishing Craft Horizons magazine and the founding and operation of Craft International magazine are documented by correspondence and subject files. Correspondence is mainly professional with some scattered personal letters. Subject files concern various organizations, individuals and events related to Slivka's work and interests. Among the writings are manuscripts, notes, and research materials for her book about Peter Voulkos; also included are shorter writings on a variety of topics, poems, 2 diaries, lectures and talks. There are many interviews with craftspeople and artists conducted by Slivka and others, some undertaken as research for articles. Photographs include views of Slivka, craftspeople she observed when traveling abroad, and artwork.
Slivka, Rose
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1947-2005 ( Box 1; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1950-2004 (Boxes 1-4: 3.6 linear feet)
Series 3: Interviews, 1974-2001 (Boxes 5-6; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 4: Writings, Notes, and Related Research, 1954-2001 (Boxes 6-11, OV 23; 4.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Subject Files, 1958-2004 (Boxes 11-18, 22, OV 23; 7.4 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1952-2006 (Boxes 18-20, OV 23; 1.9 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, circa 1947-1990s (Boxes 20-21; 1 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
Crafts expert Rose Slivka (1919-2004) was an editor, educator, and critic in New York City and East Hampton, NY. Slivka edited Craft Horizons magazine from 1957-1979, and then founded Crafts International, which published its first issue in 1980.
Rose Slivka was very active in the American Crafts Council and World Crafts Council, and promoted crafts by participating in conferences around the world, acting as a juror of competitions, writing, and teaching. The author of books and articles about crafts, including the entry on "Handicrafts" in the 1961 edition of Encyclopedia Britannica, Slivka was tireless in her search for information pertaining to crafts of all nations. Her study of the subject was integrated into a strong, far-reaching campaign to include sculpture as a craft and promote crafts on a par with fine art. She was also interested in poetry and taught courses in art criticism at New York University and the New School for Social Research.
Many of Slivka's articles on craft, painting and sculpture have been published in periodicals such as Art in America, Architectural Digest, and The New York Times. Books and exhibition catalogs include The Crafts of the Modern World (1964); The Object as Poet (1976), Renwick Gallery, Washington, DC; Peter Voulkos: A Dialogue in Clay (1978); California Clay (1979), Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam; and The Book as Art and Artist (1979), Elaine Benson Gallery, Bridgehampton, NY. Slivka's writings have been translated into at least 7 languages.
Slivka was awarded the National Endowment for the Arts Critics Fellowship in 1976 and between 1980 and 1982 conducted a research project on "Criticism and Scholarship in Modern Craft" also sponsored by the National Endowment for the Arts. She was awarded The Rhode Island School of Design President's Fellows Award in 1982, and its highest honor, the Athena Medal. In addition, she served on the boards of directors for several New York City organizations including Clayworks Studio Workshop, New York Experimental Glassworks, and Center for Book Arts.
Following her career as a magazine editor, international speaker on crafts, writer, and educator, Slivka moved to East Hampton, Long Island, where she continued to write poetry and was art critic for The East Hampton Star newspaper.
Rose Slivka's was married to sculptor David Slivka; the couple had 2 children and eventually divorced. She died of heart failure in Southampton, NY, on September 2, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original materials requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington D.C. research center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Rose Slivka papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by Slivka's daughter, Charlotte Slivka, in 2008 and 2012.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of craft expert Rose Slivka, an editor, writer, critic, and educator, measure 20.8 linear feet and date from circa 1947-2006. The papers reflect Slivka's work with associations and universities to encourage the recognition of crafts as an international and broadly defined art form. The routine business of publishing Craft Horizons magazine and the founding and operation of Craft International magazine are documented by correspondence and subject files. Correspondence is mainly professional with some scattered personal letters. Subject files concern various organizations, individuals and events related to Slivka's work and interests. Among the writings are manuscripts, notes, and research materials for her book about Peter Voulkos; also included are shorter writings on a variety of topics, poems, 2 diaries, lectures and talks. There are many interviews with craftspeople and artists conducted by Slivka and others, some undertaken as research for articles. Photographs include artwork, views of Slivka, and craftspeople she observed when traveling abroad.
Interviews with craftsmen and other artists were conducted by Rose Slivka and others. Peter Voulkos is espcially well-documented. Among the artists interviewed are: Elaine de Kooning, Philip Guston, Jack Lenor Larsen, Louise Nevelson, and David Slivka. Also found are intereviews with John Cage, Stanley Kunitz, and Rose Slivka.
American Craft Council; Cage, John, 1912-1992; Craft Horizons.; Craft International.; De Kooning, Elaine; Guston, Philip, 1913-1980; Kunitz, Stanley, 1905-2006; Larsen, Jack Lenor; Nevelson, Louise, 1899-1988; Slivka, David, 1913-; Voulkos, Peter, 1924-2002; World Crafts Council.; Art critics--New York (State)--New York; Authors--New York (State)--New York; Diaries; Editors--New York (State)--New York; Interviews; Photographs; Sound recordings; Video recordings
- Biographical Material, circa 1947-2005; Series 1; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Awards and certificates include one for service to The Commission on the Future of Washington University, Cooper-Hewitt Museum Honorary Membership in The Society of the Arts, New School for Social Research for participation in Art and the Community Institute, and University of Puerto Rico recognizing participation in the First Congress of Latin American Artisans. Calendars are annotated and contain loose notes and a few pieces of correspondence. Legal documents mainly concern a mortgage in arrears and also include a copy of Slivka's will. There is a videocassette recording her memorial service and a sound cassette of a visit with her mother.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Additional awards and certificates recognizing Craft Horizons and Craft International are found among the subject files (Series 5).
  - Astrology Reading, undated; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1979-1994; undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Biographical Notes and Resume, circa 1947-1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Calendars and Schedule, 1989-1999; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Legal Documents, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Service, Guild Hall, 2005; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Visit to Mama's Apt.", 1976; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1950-2004; Series 2; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-4
  The correspondence of Rose Slivka is both professional and personal in nature. Professional correspondence reflects her involvement with a variety of organizations and teaching activities. Correspondence concerning her editorial work includes memos and documents produced or received by Patricia Dandignac, Donald Wycoff and other staff of Craft Horizons. Due to considerable overlap between Slivka's professional and private lives, quite a bit of correspondence relates to both spheres. Personal correspondence, mostly from earlier years, concerns her husband, sculptor David Slivka, and their two children. In later years, personal correspondence appears mostly as greeting cards and notes. Most of Slivka's correspondence involves routine matters relating to the business of magazine publishing and the ideal of promoting crafts.
  Among the many attachments are: clippings, exhibition catalogs, and other printed items; photographs and slides; legal contracts and documents; resumes; and writings, such as talks, essays and poems by Slivka and others. Writings of note include "A Note on the Politics and Esthetics of a Woman's Show" by Lucy Lippard, "The Need for Museum Art in India" by Ajit Ghose, "Integrated Works" by David Davidson, and papers about various methods of casting sculpture.
  Correspondents include numerous organizations devoted to promoting and enlarging the scope of crafts, among them the American Crafts Council and World Crafts Council. Slivka corresponded with universities and schools regarding topics of interest to Craft Horizons and Craft International, showing particular interest in the Cranbrook Academy of Art and the Haystack School. A considerable amount of correspondence documents Slivka's involvement in the planning of or participating in numerous conferences and symposia as a juror, panel participant or moderator in the United States, Japan, Indonesia, Australia, and other venues. There is correspondence relating to ceramic artist Peter Voulkos and Slivka's book about him, Peter Voulkos: A Dialogue in Clay, as well as a large amount of correspondence with Lloyd Herman concerning her work on the "Object as Poet" exhibition (1977) at the Renwick Gallery. Other prominent individuals with whom Slivka corresponded are: Elaine de Kooning, Leo Castellli, Jack Lenor Larsen, Jeff Schlanger, Sam Maloof, and Nancy Hanks of the National Council on the Arts. Lastly, there is correspondence relating to Slivka's work as art critic in the 1990s for The East Hampton Star newspaper including readers' letters.
  Correspondence is filed chronologically. Subject files (Series 5) contain additional correspondence.
  - Correspondence, undated; 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10-26)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1-18)
  - Correspondence, 1978-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1-23)
- Interviews, 1974-2001; Series 3; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Interviews (32 sound cassettes, 1 sound reel, 4 videocassettes (VHS) and 8 transcripts) mostly with craftsmen and artists were conducted by Rose Slivka and others. Several interviews are with and about Peter Voulkos. Artists include Elaine de Kooning, Philip Guston, Jack Lenor Larsen, Louise Nevelson, and David Slivka. Other individuals of note are John Cage and Stanley Kunitz. Rose Slivka is the subject of two interviews, one of which focuses on Elaine de Kooning.
  - Elaine de Kooning interviewed by Frazer Dougherty, undated; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Four Bay Area Potters - Robert Arneson, James Melchert, Peter Voulkos, Charles McKee - interviewed by B. Horiuchi (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Connie Fox interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Grace Knowlton interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanley Kunitz interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jack Lenor Larsen interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mason interviewed by Rose Slivka about Peter Voulkos (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - James Melchert and Pete [Voulkos] interviewed by Rose Slivka (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Neon Joey interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Frances Senske interviewed by Rose Slivka about Peter Voulkos (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Richard Shaw interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rose Slivka interviewed by unidentified interviewer about Elaine de Kooning, undated; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Esteban Vicente interviewed by Rose Slivka, undated; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "A" interviewed by Rose Slivka (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "S" interviewed by Rose Slivka (transcript), undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - David Slivka interviewed by Doris C. Freedman, WNYC "Artists in the City", 1974; 1 sound tape reels (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peter Voulkos, Fred and Mary Marer interviewed by Rose Slivka (transcript), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Philip Guston interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1980; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Lee Hall interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1981; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Louise Nevelson interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1982; 5 sound cassettes with partial transcript. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Peter Voulkos interviewed by Gerry Williams, 1982; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Peter Voulkos at Callas interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1982; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Elaine de Kooning interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1983; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lee Hall interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1983; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - John Cage interviewed by Carl Bergstrøm-Nielsen, 1984; 1 sound cassette with letter (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Carolyn Forché interviewed by Pearl London, 1985; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stanley Kunitz interviewed by Pearl London, 1985; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stanley Kunitz interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1985; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tom Greenbaum interviewed by Rose Slvka, 1986; 3 sound cassettes with letter and transcriber's notes. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reuben Kadish interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1986; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Elaine de Kooning interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Alana Heiss interviewed by Kay Larsen, 1987; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Peter Voulkos interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1987; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Sandy Shannonhouse interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Peter Voulkos interviewed by Rose Slivka, 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Peter Voulkos interviewed by Archie Brang in Bergen, Norway (1955) and "Voulkos at Callas Aug. 93" (1993), 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - June Kaneko interviewed by Rose Slivka at Long House Reserve, 2001; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Writings, Notes and Related Research, 1954-2001; Series 4; 4.8 Linear feet Boxes 6-11, OV 23
  Rose Slivka's writings include 2 diaries that record dreams, reminiscences, health concerns, and professional and personal activities. Miscellaneous writings are manuscripts, drafts and fragments of articles, reports, essays, and other shorter pieces; many are untitled and a high percentage are about crafts. Among her lectures and talks are recordings of symposia and panel discussions in which she was a participant. Notes include meeting notes, schedules, phone messages, names and addresses; 9 notebooks contain similar material. Slivka's writings on Peter Voulkos include several articles and a book, Peter Voulkos: A Dialogue with Clay. Voulkos research and reference materials for the book include scattered items relating to earlier articles.
  The majority of writings by others are lectures and talks, including panel discussions and symposia, several of which featured Slivka as a moderator or co-host. Included are recordings (3 videocassettes (VHS) and 6 sound cassettes) of a symposium on "Craft Today," readings by poets and painters, a gallery talk by Elaine de Kooning, a conversation among 3 unidentified Haystack School artists, and panel discussions about The Club and on art criticism. Other writings include artists' staements and Alice Jane King's 1982 dissertation, "America's Contemporary Craftsmen."
  - By Slivka (Box 6)
    - Diaries, 1987 August 12-1988 December 20 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Diaries, 1991 April 19-1992 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-1999 (Box 7, Folder 14-21)
    - Italy, 1960; undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Peter Voulkos, undated; 1978 (Box 8, Folder 2-10)
      Oversize material housed in OV 23
    - Peter Voulkos, Early Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Peter Voulkos, Book Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Peter Voulkos, Working Copy of Final Manuscript, circa 1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Peter Voulkos, Galley Proofs, circa 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    - Peter Voulkos, Research and Reference Material, 1965-1999; undated (Box 9, Folder 1-12)
    - Lecture/Dialogue, Dorothy Ruddick and Rose Slivka, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1980; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Lectures and Talks, undated (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
    - Lectures and Talks, Untitled Panel Discussion moderated by Gaby Rogers, undated; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Artists Alliance: On Living with Art" featuring Phyllis Braff and Rose Slivka, 1988; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Craft at Mid-Century" Panel Discussion (transcript), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18-20)
    - Lectures and Talks, Untitled, 1994; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Notebooks, undated; 1984-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
    - Notes, undated; 1955-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6-12)
    - Poems, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Poetry and Visual Arts" Exhibition (circa 1976), Research Materials, circa 1972-1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - By Others (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Artists' Statements, 1978; undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Dissertation, "America's Contemporary Craftsmen" by Alice Jane King, George Washington University, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Craft Today" Symposium, undated; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Lectures and Talks, Elaine De Kooning Gallery Talk at the Whitney Museum, undated; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Haystack" Panel Discusson with David Zata (voice 1) and 3 Unidentified Artists (voices 2-4), moderated by Lloyd Herman, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Lectures and Talks, Patton Miller, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Lectures and Talks, "The Club" Panel Discussion, Landmark Gallery, 1981; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Do Critics Matter Anymore?," unidentified speaker, 1988; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lectures and Talks, "The Summer of 1957," Rose Slivka co-host, 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lectures and Talks, "Art Criticism: Whose Truth?" Panel Discussion, moderated by Rose Slivka, 2001; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Readings by Poets and Painters, 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Report on Eastern Shore Crafts Industry, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Amy Zerner, Slivka, and Others, 1992-1993; 8 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
      Zerner, Slivka and others discuss plans for the organization and design of a book by Zerner.
  - Oversized Writings, Notes and Related Research - Peter Voulkos from Box 8, Folder 2, undated (Box OV 23)
- Subject Files, 1958-2004; Series 5; 7.4 Linear feet Boxes 11-18, 22, OV 23
  Subject files consist of varying combinations of materials - correspondence, writings, photographs, printed items, and audiovisual recordings - that document organizations, activities, individuals, subjects, and events reflecting Slivka's work and interests. American Crafts Council, Center for Book Arts, Craft Horizons, Craft International, Sam Maloof, New York University, Poetry Workshops, Peter Voulkos exhibition (circa 1977), and World Crafts Council are among the most extensively documented subjects. Other files of particular interest are "Material as Metaphor," a College Art Association panel discussion with Peter Voulkos, Louise Nevelson, John Cage and Jacqueline Rice organized and moderated by Slivka; and a file titled Paul and Ellen Russotto that contains founding documentation of the Society for the Preservation of the Archives of the New York School.
  - 7 Bank Street, New York City, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 68 Copeces Lane, East Hampton, NY, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - American Crafts Council/American Craftsmen's Council, 1958-1968; undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - American Crafts Council, circa 1970s-1979 (Box 11, Folder 12-17)
  - American Crafts Council Awards Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "The Art/Craft Connection U.S.A.: California and the Culture", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Art Today, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Artists' Jewelry, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Atelier 17, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Benton Gallery, undated; 1988 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Bohary, James, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Book Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Brady, Peter, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - George Braziller, Inc., 1996 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Buggiani, Palo, undated; 1974-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Castelli, Leo, 1974-1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Center for Book Arts, undated (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
  - "Century of Ceramics" Lecture, Museum News and Philbrook Material, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Chihuly, Dale, 1977-1970; undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Clayworks Studio Workshop, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Collecting, undated; 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Craft Alliance (St. Louis), 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - "?Craft/Art?" Panel Discussion, The Noyes Museum, Oceanville, NJ, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Craft Horizons, undated; 1955-1979; Oversized material housed in OV 23 (Box 12, Folder 13-22)
  - Craft Horizons - Society of Publication Designers Award of Excellence, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Craft Horizons - World Crafts Council, Mexico, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Craft International, 1980-1987; Oversized material housed in Box 22. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Craft International -- Art in Public Spaces, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Craft International -- Board of Directors Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Craft International -- Bordaz, Jacques and Louise, "Turkey", 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Craft International -- Castle, Wendell, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Craft International -- Center for Book Arts, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Craft Internationa l -- Chaleff, Paul, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Craft International -- Gerald Clark Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Craft International -- Cody, Judy/Workbench the Gallery, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Craft International -- Cooper-Hewitt Museum, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Craft International -- Correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 13, Folder 11-13)
  - Craft International -- Craft and Folk Art Museums, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Craft International -- The Crafts Center, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Craft International -- Creative Arts Workshop, Hartford, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Craft International -- Davison, David, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 17)